A mysterious key that stirs human desire.
勾起人類欲望的神祕鑰匙
It summons the devil and starts a game of death.
它能召喚惡魔，開啟生死遊戲
A devil's key.
這就是惡魔鑰匙
When I returned home to find out who killed my father,
當我返回日本尋找殺父凶手時
-the organization Gungnir was waiting. -The ultimate ACMA:GAME begins.
-永恆之槍組織在等著我 -終極ACMA:GAME開始了
A tournament is being held on a deserted island
他們在一座荒島上進行一場錦標賽
to collect all 99 keys in the world.
目的是集齊世上的99把惡魔鑰匙
The last participant to arrive
隨後，最後一名參賽者到場
was my best friend, Yuki.
她是我的好友悠季
Yuki,
悠季
where did you get that key?
那把鑰匙…
A little present from me.
那是我送的禮物
Yuki Manabe
真鍋悠季
developed OROCHI, the future of AI technology.
她開發了下一代人工智慧大蛇
She is naturally gifted.
她擁有天賦的才華
Why are you here?
妳怎麼會來這裡？
Everybody has something they want.
誰都會有欲望
She may appear gentle,
她看起來溫婉文靜
but her heart is stained with greed,
但內心同樣充滿欲望
just like the rest of you.
就和你們一樣
You sound like a sore loser.
你是被奪走鑰匙後不服氣嗎？
You only cling on to your Dragon King title because you have a key.
靠惡魔鑰匙當上龍王的人 可沒資格說我
No way, is that true?
是真的嗎？
Anyway, how does she know Teruasa?
話說，她和照朝是什麼關係？
Silence!
安靜
I've got something fun to show you.
我給你們看看一個有趣的東西吧
There were some unexpected casualties
在國外的比賽會場
after an attempted escape from one of the foreign game arenas.
有參賽者因為試圖逃跑而意外死亡
This recording is from 30 minutes ago.
這是30分鐘前拍到的畫面
What happened to them?
他們怎麼了？
That drone! That drone must have killed them!
無人機，一定是無人機殺死了他們
What drone?
什麼無人機？
Nothing…
沒什麼…
You can only tell if you go outside, but this island is under surveillance.
你到外面走一走就會發現 這座小島被監視了
Island?
小島？
We're on an island?
我們在一座島上？
From what I saw yesterday, it's about 20 km all the way around.
根據我昨天的觀察 小島的周長大約有20公里
No supermarkets, convenience stores or traffic lights.
島上沒有超市、便利商店和訊號
An uninhabited island.
這是一座無人島
And the drone?
那無人機呢？
A drone with a bomb attached.
那是裝有炸彈的自爆式無人機
I wonder what it was intended for?
那些無人機是做什麼用的？
Better not to think about it too much.
你們不需要想多餘的事
Just concentrate on the game.
專心比賽就好了
If you win the game and collect more keys,
如果你們能贏得比賽並收集更多鑰匙
you can have whatever you want.
什麼欲望都能實現
Every last one of you needs those keys, or am I mistaken?
你們每個人都需要鑰匙，不是嗎？
Is it fun? Playing with our minds? Making us fight?
蠱惑人心 讓我們互相爭鬥，很好玩嗎？
What do you want us for?
你到底為何叫我們來？
Can you stop getting in his way?
可以不要打斷他嗎？
I just want to focus on the game.
我只想專心比賽
-This man is a murderer. -Even if he's a dictator,
-這個人是殺人凶手 -就算他是個獨裁者
it makes no difference to me.
我也不在乎
I'm glad you understand.
很高興你明白這一點
Call me a dictator if you like,
你們儘管叫我獨裁者吧
but small sacrifices have to be made for the greater good.
為了大義 做出小小的犧牲是不可避免的
I don't know what greater good you're after,
我不知道你的大義是什麼
but are you referring to my father?
但你指的是我父親嗎？
Are you calling my father's life a small sacrifice?
你稱我父親的死是小犧牲？
Don't move!
不准動
Toba?
鳥羽
The second match of the first round starts in one hour.
第一輪的第二場比賽在一小時後開始
Then see you later.
等等見囉
See you in the next game, huh?
下一場比賽請多指教
Yukky.
小悠季
Yuki, why are you doing this?
悠季，為什麼？
I had no choice.
我不能不來
Yuki.
悠季
They took your mother and brother hostage?
妳媽媽和弟弟被綁架了？
If I lose the game,
如果我輸掉比賽
they're going to kill my mom and brother.
他們就會殺死我媽媽和弟弟
Ui.
初
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
Don't you care about Yuki?
你不擔心悠季嗎？
There's only one thing she can do.
她能做的只有一件事
Win the game.
那就是贏得比賽
Don't look at me! I'm not doing that.
不行，我沒辦法喔
Her family's lives depend on it.
這關係到她家人的性命
True. But don't forget,
對，但是別忘記
all of our lives hang on this tournament.
這個錦標賽關係到我們所有人的性命
Including yours
包括你的
and mine.
還有我的
but we've dealt with it here.
但我們已經在這裡解決了
Yes.
是
Gonna steal the phone?
你想偷衛星電話？
I guess you think you can contact the outside world,
你想在比賽結束前聯繫外界
and save Yuki's family before the game ends?
救出悠季的家人？
But
但是
you'll never get away with it with those guards.
有那些守衛在，你是偷不了的
OUT OF RANGE
（無訊號）
There's no signal on the island.
這座島上沒有訊號
Oh, really?
是嗎？
The footage from the other arena was recorded just 30 minutes ago.
其他賽場的影片是30分鐘前拍下來的
There must be a secret communications facility on the island.
這說明島上肯定有祕密通訊設施
Well, now that I think about it,
現在回想起來
I saw a huge radio tower.
我有看到一個超大的電波塔
That's where the drone attacked us.
我就是在那附近被無人機攻擊的
Was it protecting the radio tower?
它在看守電波塔嗎？
Who knows?
誰知道？
After that I went to the beach and there was a boat just sitting there.
後來我去了海邊 看到一艘船停靠在那裡
I thought that could be my escape route, so I went to check it,
我心想如果發生什麼事 就可以藉此脫身
but another drone appeared, and bam!
此時另一架無人機飛過來，然後爆炸
Just as if I was being played with.
感覺我被人玩弄了
Really pissed me off.
真是氣死我了
Yuki.
悠季
I think I can help your mom and brother.
我應該能救出你媽媽和弟弟
Come in.
進來吧
WATCH OUT FOR DRONES HOTEL
（小心無人機，飯店）
-A radio tower? -Yes.
-電波塔？ -對
I think we can call for help from there.
我們應該可以在那裡呼救
I'll try and get them to safety before the game is finished.
我會想辦法在比賽結束前救他們
But what if something happens to you?
但是你要是出事了怎麼辦？
I'll be fine.
別擔心
It's nothing like what I went through
我在海外尋找惡魔鑰匙時
when I was looking for devil's keys abroad.
曾多次化解危機
But promise you'll be careful.
但你還是要小心
The second match of round one is about to begin.
第一輪的第二場比賽即將開始
-Players are asked… -Yuki.
-請參賽者… -悠季
-…to move to the game room. -Any idea where your family is?
-…到遊戲室集合 -你知道他們被帶去哪裡嗎？
No. None.
不知道
I could track them down with an Internet connection.
如果能連接網路，我就能追蹤到他們
Oh, right!
對了
Teruasa, I'll do anything to help Yuki's family.
照朝君 我會盡力救出悠季的媽媽和弟弟
Will you take me to the radio tower?
帶我去找電波塔吧
But wouldn't you rather have OROCHI with you in the game?
但是在比賽中 有大蛇幫你會比較放心吧？
If it'll help my family,
為了家人
I'll manage on my own.
我會堅強起來的
Okay.
好
I know you can do it.
妳可以的
I need you to listen carefully to what I'm about to say.
悠季，從現在開始認真聽我說
You've reached Teruasa Oda.
你好，我是織田
I can't answer the phone right now.
我現在無法接聽電話
Hyodo.
兵頭
He wasn't at work either?
你在他的工作地點也找不到他嗎？
No.
對
He said he wanted to watch me fight, so I brought tickets.
他說他想看我比賽 所以我拿了票要給他
FUJIN SHOW 2025
（2025年風神賽）
WATCH OUT FOR DRONES
（小心無人機）
BEWARE OF ROCKS
（當心岩石，小心無人機）
You heard about the radio tower?
你聽說了電波塔的事？
TOURNAMENT ROUND ONE ARENA ONE
（錦標賽第一輪，第一會場）
Thanks for telling us about it.
謝謝你告訴我們這個資訊
You think I was trying to help?
妳以為我是好心相助？
SENYA UESUGI VS YUKI MANABE
（上杉潛夜對真鍋悠季）
-Weren't you? -No way.
-不是嗎？ -當然不是
Of course not.
那怎麼可能呢？
I made a bet to see whether I'd beat you first,
我是在打賭我贏妳更快
or Terurin would rescue your family first.
還是小照照救出妳的家人更快
Playing against a little newbie like you wasn't quite doing it for me.
因為和妳這樣的新手比賽 沒什麼挑戰性
So shall we get on with it?
那我們開始吧
Senya will do his best to mess with your head.
潛夜一定會擾亂妳的思緒
Whatever the game is,
不管比賽的內容是什麼
the winner is one who masters manipulation.
最終誰能夠掌控比賽，誰就能獲勝
So keep up a strong guard and don't let him read you.
因此，為了不被他看穿 妳一定要提高警覺
Then you can take the lead and control him.
這樣才能掌控比賽並控制對手
Wait!
等一下
I've never started a game before,
我從沒有用過惡魔鑰匙
so I don't have a devil power.
所以我還沒有惡魔之力
Is it fun to beat me with such a big advantage?
我們現在實力懸殊 這樣打敗我不會很沒意思嗎？
Or maybe…
還是說…
you're intimidated by the creator of something as amazing as OROCHI.
你害怕我這個開發了大蛇的工程師？
You're telling me.
這還用說？
I expect Terurin's filled your head with tactics, but…
看來小照照教了妳不少戰術
fine by me. Go for it.
好，請便
Come out, devil!
惡魔，出來吧
TOURNAMENT ONE ARENA TWO
（錦標賽第一輪，第二會場）
MITSURU ASAI VS AKIRA MORI
（淺井滿對毛利明）
Go on.
請便
I summon the devil.
召喚惡魔
Welcome to the world of ACMA:GAME.
歡迎來到ACMA:GAME世界
Here by your summoning, I am the game master, Elva.
我是應召喚現身的遊戲管理者埃爾瓦
I am a very noble devil,
作為高貴的惡魔
so I will be a fair judge to you both.
我會做出公正的評判
It's a pleasure, El-chin.
初次見面，小埃埃
You're quite the gentleman compared to that Gado-chin.
跟卡多哥比起來，你真有紳士風度
Please accept my gratitude.
多謝誇獎
Would you be so kind as to state your demands?
請說出你們的要求
I'd like to make you give me a kiss,
我想要你親我一下
but I guess I'll follow the tournament rules.
不過我還是遵守錦標賽的規則吧
I demand control of her life.
我要掌控她的性命
Same here.
我也一樣
I accept your requests.
我同意你們的要求
Now for your oaths.
那就宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
-I swear on the devil.
-我向惡魔宣誓
Oaths accepted.
我接受你們的宣誓
This time, the game is called…
這次的遊戲叫…
"Gold Gun &amp; Silver Gun."
“金槍和銀槍”
Please go ahead. Kindly open the boxes.
請打開面前的箱子
Robbery and citizen?
強盜和市民？
El-chin, how do we play?
小埃埃，這個遊戲怎麼玩？
You are in the Old West, the American Frontier.
遊戲時間是美國西部開拓時代 地點為美國舊西部
You find yourself in a bank in the city.
現在你們兩人 在某個城市的一家銀行裡
Really? Do we get money?
真的嗎？能拿錢嗎？
It's just the game's setting, right?
這是遊戲的設定吧？
There are $1,000 dollars in the bank.
現在假設銀行裡有一千美元
Senya, if it were up to you,
潛夜先生，如果是你
what would you do with the money?
你會拿這筆錢怎麼辦？
I'd take my gun and steal it all.
我會用槍把錢搶走
You'll get caught.
這樣會被逮捕的
Is that how the game works?
遊戲是這樣設定的嗎？
If you wish to steal the money press the "robbery" button.
如果你想搶走金錢 那就按“強盜”按鈕
But if you prefer not to, please press the "citizen" button.
如果不想搶錢，那就按“市民”按鈕
Now what?
然後呢？
I will say the word "judge."
然後我會說“開始判定”
The room will become dark for ten seconds.
這時遊戲室會變暗十秒
If you think your opponent has pressed "robbery,"
如果你們認為對手按了“強盜”鍵
then while it is dark, please pull the trigger on your gun.
請在遊戲室變暗時扣下扳機
Will we die?
我們不會死吧？
Please rest assured,
放心
the gun will shoot flames and make a flashy bang,
槍只會發出巨響和噴出火焰
but no one will be harmed.
不會傷害到對方
Nothing?
沒反應？
It can only shoot during the darkness.
它只能在黑暗中射擊
Incidentally, when you shoot, it automatically hits the target.
另外，如果你們開槍 槍會自動擊中對手
Either of you may fire your weapon.
你們任何一方都可以開槍
If neither of you shoots within ten seconds,
如果你們都不開槍，十秒後
the darkness ends.
黑暗會自動消失
Shoot or wait ten seconds.
開槍或等待十秒
RULE ONE
（規則一）
If you choose to be a robber and don't get shot, you win the money.
如果選擇當強盜的人沒被槍擊 那麼金庫裡的錢由這個人獲得
If you choose to be a citizen, you get nothing.
選擇當市民的人一分錢也得不到
RULE 2
（規則二）
What happens if we both choose to be robbers?
如果兩個人都選擇當強盜要怎麼算？
The person who shoots first wins the money.
先開槍的人能贏得獎金
RULE 3
（規則三）
Then surely it's best to be a robber?
那就只能選強盜囉？
If you accidentally shoot someone who chose to be a citizen－
如果你們誤射選擇當市民的人…
Yes?
會怎麼樣？
Please excuse me.
不好意思
RULE 4
（規則四）
If you accidentally shoot a citizen, there will be a $3,000 fine.
如果誤射市民，要處以三千美元罰款
And if a citizen shoots a robber?
如果市民開槍射擊強盜呢？
The money in the safe is defended.
保險箱內的錢就安全了
RULE 5 - DEFENSE
（規則五：防衛）
Should I be citizen or a robber?
我要選擇當市民還是當強盜？
To shoot or not to shoot.
要開槍還是不開槍
What?
什麼？
What's happening?
怎麼回事？
Yuki, you used your key for the first time,
悠季小姐第一次使用惡魔鑰匙
so your devil power is released.
所以妳解鎖了惡魔之力
I just paused time for a little moment.
我暫時讓時間靜止了
My devil power?
我的惡魔之力嗎？
Yuki, your devil power is
悠季小姐的惡魔之力是
Contagion Program.
“感染程式”
It is also known as the contagious power to command.
它也叫做“感染指令”
Contagious power to command?
感染指令？
You choose an object to command,
妳可以選擇對一個物品發出指令
and when that object is in your opponent's hands,
當這個物品在對方手上時
they will subconsciously follow whatever command you gave.
對手會不自覺地遵守妳的指令
So if I tell this object to laugh,
也就是說 假如我對這個物品發出笑的指令
then give it to him,
然後把它拿給潛夜
whenever he touches it, he'll laugh for no reason?
他碰到這個物品時會不自覺地笑？
Yes, exactly as you imagine.
對，一點也沒錯
But, how am I supposed to use that to my advantage?
但是我要怎麼利用這個能力呢？
Do you presume that I will answer every little question?
別以為妳問什麼我都會回答
Humans are such inferior creatures.
人類真是下等又庸俗
Now I'll reset the safe.
現在我要重置保險箱
Please place your cases in front of you.
請將你們的箱子放到面前
Let the game Gold Gun &amp; Silver Gun commence!
“金槍和銀槍”遊戲開始
GOLD GUN &amp; SILVER GUN SET ONE
（金槍和銀槍，第一局）
Like I said before, I'm not gonna go easy on you.
我先聲明，我是不會放水的
The word "defeat" is not in my dictionary.
我的字典裡沒有“失敗”這個詞
Then allow me to write it in for you.
那我就幫你補上
So, will you steal or defend the money?
那麼，你們要奪走還是看守金錢？
If I win $5,000 now…
如果我這一局能贏五千美元…
WHICH TO CHOOSE? ROBBERY - CITIZEN
（如何選擇？強盜，市民）
…it won't matter if I lose $3,000 for killing a citizen later on.
下一局即使因為誤射市民 被罰三千美元，這個結果也能承受
THE CHOICE HAS TO BE ROBBERY
（絕對要選擇當強盜）
So I'll be a robber.
那就選強盜
But wait.
等一下
He wants the money, same as me.
對方也和我一樣想要這筆錢
If I press "robbery," we'll both have to shoot each other.
如果我按“強盜”鍵 我們會開槍互相射擊
So perhaps I should be a citizen and get him to shoot me.
這樣的話 這一局我可以當市民，讓對方開槍
That's a good plan.
好主意
But if he sees through my plan, and doesn't shoot,
但是如果他看穿了我的計畫 選擇不開槍
then I'll lose all of the money.
錢會被他全部拿走
Right! I'll choose "citizen," and wait for a few seconds after it goes dark.
有了，我選擇當市民 然後在黑暗中等待幾秒
WILL THE OPPONENT SHOOT?
（對手會開槍嗎？）
If he still doesn't shoot, then I'll shoot him.
如果他還是不開槍 那我就開槍射擊他
DO I SHOOT?
（我要開槍嗎？）
With this strategy, I'm ready for anything－
這個策略可以應對所有情況…
No I'm not.
不行
He could be a citizen.
他也可以當市民
If he is, and I shoot him,
這時我如果開槍
I'll pay a $3,000 penalty.
會被罰三千美元
You look like you're getting in a muddle,
妳好像在忙著思考策略
but there's no point strategizing.
但這個遊戲沒有策略可言
It's not about gains and losses.
我們要考慮的不是得失…
It's about analyzing the opponent's thoughts.
這個遊戲在於分析對手的想法
It's about controlling
…而是操縱對手的想法
YUKI CHOOSES TO BE A CITIZEN
（悠季選擇當市民）
Time to judge.
開始判定
He fired!
他開槍了
Senya chose to be a robber,
潛夜先生選擇當強盜
and shot Yuki, a citizen!
並向市民悠季小姐開了槍
Senya incurs a penalty of $3,000.
因此潛夜先生被罰三千美元
Senya loves a thrill, so he'd never choose to be a citizen.
潛夜喜歡冒險，他不會選擇當市民的
My analysis was correct.
我的分析是對的
What a letdown.
好失望
I had high hopes you'd be clever enough to attack in the first set.
我還以為聰明的妳 會在第一局就開始進攻
You won't beat me if you're on the defensive from the start.
從一開始就防守是贏不了我的
Pigtail girl.
辮子妹
Did I piss you off? I don't mind if you're mad.
妳生氣了？生氣也沒關係
Emotional people are the easiest to manipulate.
感情用事的人最容易操控了
You're an attention seeker.
你這個人愛出風頭
There's nothing you love more than seeing a look of surprise
你最喜歡看的就是
on your opponent's face.
對手露出驚愕的表情
So obviously someone like you would fire from the start.
像你這樣的人 一定會在第一局就開槍
You really are
你還真的是
pretty simple, aren't you?
很容易看透呢
Would you look at that?
瞧一瞧
You're unexpectedly feisty, aren't you?
妳反過來挑釁我了
Do you like this kind of thing, Senya?
潛夜先生喜歡這樣嗎？
I don't just like it.
我不僅僅喜歡
I love it.
我簡直愛死了
The safe is reset.
現在重置保險箱
Why are you following me?
妳為什麼要跟蹤我？
I－
我…
Earlier, what were you talking about in Yuki's room?
剛才你們在悠季的房間裡說了什麼？
Go back to the hotel.
快回飯店
Just tell me.
告訴我吧
Why can't I know?
為什麼不讓我知道？
You don't care about Yuki.
妳又不在乎悠季的事
-But I care about you. -What?
-但我在乎你啊 -什麼？
I mean, because you have my key and you control my life.
我是說，因為我把鑰匙和性命 都交付給你了
-A drone's seen us. Run. -What?
-無人機發現我們了，快跑 -什麼？
What should we do?
我們要怎麼辦？
-Jump! -What?
-快跳 -什麼？
$1,000.
一千美元
Will you steal or defend the money?
你們要奪走還是看守金錢？
GOLD GUN &amp; SILVER GUN SET TWO
（金槍和銀槍，第二局）
A grand is no good to me.
一千美元對我來說沒用
The real problem is
重點是
how do I regain the lead from Yukky?
我要如何從小悠季手中奪回主導權？
Maybe I'll try the strategy I came up with earlier.
也許我可以試試之前想好的策略
Why would he blurt out his plan?
把自己的想法說出來是什麼意思？
Is he trying to trick me?
他是想藉此混淆我嗎？
Even though you're a total adrenaline junkie,
不管你多喜歡追求刺激
you're not going to shoot me this time?
這次你肯定不會開槍吧？
If you risk it just for $1,000,
為了區區一千美元冒險
it'll be tragic to see you get another penalty, don't you think?
要是再被罰款，那就慘了
Well,
那麼
what will it be?
我會怎麼做呢？
I'm not robbing this time either.
第二局我也不搶奪金錢
I'll be a citizen.
我要當市民
YUKI CHOOSES TO BE A CITIZEN
（悠季選擇當市民）
Make your judgment.
開始判定
He fired!
他開槍了
Senya chose to be a robber, and shot Yuki, a citizen!
潛夜先生選擇當強盜 並向市民悠季小姐開槍了
Senya gets another $3,000 penalty.
因此潛夜先生再次被罰三千美元
Just like I thought.
果然如我所想
His gambler's pride got in the way, and he tried to do something unexpected.
出於賭徒的驕傲 他想要的是以智取勝
So he dared to shoot when he shouldn't have.
所以他敢於在不應該開槍的時候開槍
At this rate, if I keep winding him up, he'll get more and more frustrated,
照這樣下去，如果我繼續激怒他 他會越來越焦躁
and I'll win.
那樣我就贏了
Senya,
潛夜君
you've got a stubborn streak.
你是不是有點固執了？
Not a good trait for a gambler.
合格的賭徒可不會這樣
Oh, please.
拜託
Then let me show you just how stubborn I can be.
我就讓妳看看，我可以多固執
Now what's this, Senya?
這是怎樣，潛夜先生？
You've thrown away the silver gun?
你怎麼把銀槍扔掉了？
That's right. I don't need it in the next set.
沒錯，我下一局不打算用槍
What do you make of that, Yukky?
小悠季，妳怎麼分析我這個舉動？
Safe reset.
現在重置保險箱
Tell me what Gungnir's purpose is.
請告訴我永恆之槍的目的
I want to beat him.
我想打敗他
To do that, I need to know what you're after.
所以我需要知道你們的目的
I can tell you,
我可以告訴你
but once you know, you can't go back.
但你知道以後，就不能回頭了
I don't care.
沒有關係
That's what I came here for.
這就是我來這裡的目的
I thought we were going to die.
我以為我們死定了
Teruasa, haven't we gone quite far off route?
照朝君 我們是不是徹底偏離路線了？
What's that app?
那是什麼應用程式？
Nice to meet you! I'm AI OROCHI.
初次見面，我是人工智慧大蛇
Where's the radio tower?
電波塔在哪裡？
That's what you're looking for?
你要找電波塔？
Yes!
對啊
To save Yuki's mom and her brother, Kazuma.
為了要救出悠季的媽媽和她弟弟一馬
-Yukari, will you wait here? -Yukari?
-紫，妳在這裡等我 -紫？
I'm going to the radio tower alone.
我自己去電波塔那邊
Wait!
等等
You can't just leave me here.
我不要一個人待在這裡
Will you carry me?
你背我
She's kinda selfish.
她好任性
GOLD GUN &amp; SILVER GUN SET THREE
（金槍和銀槍，第三局）
$1,000.
一千美元
Will you steal or defend the money?
你們要奪走還是看守金錢？
I've chosen already.
我選好了
He threw away his gun,
他把自己的槍扔掉了
but I bet he'll shoot me anyway!
但我猜他一定會開槍
I don't know how he's going to do it
雖然我不知道他會用什麼手段
but this guy is a sucker for doing things others can't.
他會因為 做了別人做不到的事而喜不自勝
So I'm going for the same again.
所以這一局我還是和之前一樣
YUKI CHOOSES TO BE A CITIZEN
（悠季選擇當市民）
Judge.
開始判定
What? He's not gonna shoot?
他不開槍嗎？
Why not?
為什麼？
Then should I shoot? What should I do?
那我要開槍嗎？怎麼辦？
That's right, Yukky.
嗨，小悠季
Since neither of you fired this time,
這次兩人均未開槍
as the robber, Senya wins $1,000.
因此選擇當強盜的潛夜先生 獲得一千美元
I thought I could read him, but he saw right through me.
我以為看穿了對手，結果卻被他看穿
Why would you be a citizen when I chucked away my gun like that?
我好不容易把槍扔了 妳怎麼還選擇當市民？
Maybe those other wins were just flukes?
難道妳剛才都是靠僥倖贏的嗎？
What are you going on about?
你說什麼？
I wouldn't get too carried away when you only won back $1,000.
才贏回一千美元而已 請不要得意忘形
It's kind of a letdown.
好失望
I was expecting big things from you.
我還以為你準備好
I had high hopes you'd pick up the gun and show me what you're made of.
要把扔掉的槍撿回來 向我展現出你的實力了呢
What's this?
奇怪
Isn't that…
這不是…
exactly what I said to you earlier?
我剛才跟妳說的話嗎？
What a letdown.
好失望
I had high hopes you'd be clever enough to attack in the first set.
我還以為聰明的妳 會在第一局就開始進攻
Everything's going completely backwards from the first set.
局面徹底翻轉了
He's suddenly taken control.
不知不覺就被他奪下主導權
I can't let this continue.
不能再這樣下去
The safe is reset.
現在重置保險箱
GOLD GUN &amp; SILVER GUN SET FOUR
（金槍和銀槍，第四局）
$10,000!
一萬美元
My luck is back.
我的運氣來了
Let's do this. I don't need my gun in this set either.
好，我這一局也不用槍
Again?
又來了？
She's only a childhood friend.
她只是你小時候的朋友而已
You shouldn't put yourself in danger like this.
不必為了她做這麼危險的事吧？
Didn't you come here
你來這裡
to avenge your father's death?
不是要為父親報仇嗎？
That's not the only reason.
是沒錯，但不僅僅是為了這個目的
What's the other reason?
還有其他目的嗎？
There it is. We found it.
在那裡，找到了
I'm ready.
我選好了
You take all the time you need to think, okay?
妳可以慢慢考慮
In this game, the more you think, the murkier it gets.
在這個遊戲裡，想得越多會越迷茫
What would you do,
我該怎麼辦？
Teruasa?
照朝君
If you dwell too much on the enemy, you'll lose sight of your own strategy.
如果過於關注妳的敵人 就會忘記自己的策略
You need to have an accurate understanding of your enemy's strengths.
妳需要準確評估對手的能力 這很重要
Teruasa is so good at this because he can do that without trying.
照朝君很厲害 他能輕而易舉做到這點
I've gotta figure out how to do the same thing.
我也要想辦法做到這點
YUKI CHOOSES TO BE A ROBBER
（悠季選擇當強盜）
Judge.
開始判定
What?
什麼？
Two shots?
有兩聲槍響？
Senya chose to be a robber,
潛夜先生選擇當強盜
and shot Yuki first, who was also a robber.
並首先向同為強盜的悠季小姐開槍
Senya wins $10,000!
因此一萬美元由潛夜先生獲得
What? How did you shoot me?
為什麼？你是怎麼開槍的？
And how were you so quick?
而且你還能在我之前開槍
Did you use a devil power?
你使用了惡魔之力？
Wrong!
不對
During the second set,
在第二局中
I checked that pulling the trigger before the judgment
我確認了在判定之前扣扳機
would count as firing a shot.
也算成功開槍
Once that was confirmed, in the fourth set,
確認這一點後，在第四局中
I picked up the gun, pulled back the trigger, and chucked it away.
我把槍撿起來 扣下扳機，然後再扔開
The gun doesn't have to aim at the opponent to hit the target.
槍不需要瞄準對手也能擊中目標
What a comeback!
大逆轉！
The safe is reset.
現在重置保險箱
NO OPEN FLAMES - HIGH VOLTAGE
（禁止明火，高壓電）
-I'll put you down. -Okay.
-我放妳下來了 -好
A bomb?
有炸彈？
It's good you noticed that, Teruasa.
照朝君，你注意到了，太好了
We managed to lose the drone and went off route.
我們被無人機追擊，偏離了路線
Why do you think we found it so easily?
但為什麼能這麼輕易發現它？
It was a trap?
這是陷阱？
Yes.
對
Senya said something similar happened to them.
潛夜遭無人機襲擊後 說他遭遇過類似的事
Just as if I was being played with. Really pissed me off.
感覺我被人玩弄了，真是氣死我了
Being played with? How do you mean?
被人玩弄？什麼意思？
OROCHI, do you know how to disable it?
大蛇，你知道怎麼拆除它嗎？
I need to search what type of detonator it is,
我需要查詢這個爆炸裝置的類型
so start the computer and connect me to the Internet.
請打開電腦，連接網路
DETONATION ACTIVATED
（炸彈啟動）
What's happening?
你做了什麼？
That looks like a countdown!
它看起來在倒數計時
Just as I thought.
如我所料
We've been forced into a game designed by Gungnir.
我們被迫參與了永恆之槍設計的遊戲
It looks like you have to enter a four-digit code to disarm it.
在這裡輸入四位數字 似乎可以解除爆炸裝置
Our latitude or longitude? Or how many steps it took to get here?
是經度或緯度嗎？ 還是我們到這裡的步數？
None of those are four digits…
這些都不是四位數
This isn't the time for thinking!
現在不是考慮這個的時候
We need to get out of here!
我們得趕快離開這裡
"Believe in the path you are on. A new path will appear."
“相信你走的道路 這樣就能開闢新道路”
Maybe it's a hint.
這是線索嗎？
So, Yukky,
小悠季
shall we finish this?
在這一局決勝負吧？
GOLD GUN &amp; SILVER GUN SET FIVE
（金槍和銀槍，第五局）
$5,000 in the bank for set five.
第五局的金額是五千美元
Senya,
潛夜君
shall we crank things up a notch?
你想不想再刺激一點？
What do you mean?
什麼？什麼意思？
Shall we swap our cases?
我們要不要互換箱子？
So you decide if I'm a robber or citizen,
你來決定我當強盜還是當市民
and I'll decide if you're a robber or citizen.
我也來決定你當強盜還是當市民
are you worried you won't be in control?
掌控權不在自己手上 你會不會感到不安？
El-chin, is that even allowed?
小埃埃，這樣可以嗎？
If both parties agree, I'll allow it.
如果你們商量好，那我就同意
How exciting. I'm in!
有意思，我同意
I'm loving the spontaneous exchange,
我喜歡這樣臨時交換
but if you think about it, we both have to be citizens.
但仔細想想 我們是不是只能選擇當市民？
Well, what will it be?
你會怎麼選呢？
I'll make you a citizen.
我選擇讓妳當市民
Then I don't have to worry about you stealing the money,
這樣我就不擔心妳搶奪金錢了
or about getting a penalty for shooting you.
也不用擔心貿然開槍後被罰款
Surely you're thinking the same.
當然，妳肯定也是這樣想的
So I'm going for "citizen."
所以我要選市民
If that's what you think, go for it.
如果你這樣想，那就按“市民”鍵吧
I don't know what you're thinking,
雖然我不知道妳在想什麼
but however you look at it, "citizen" is the only choice.
但不管妳怎麼想 “市民”是唯一的選擇
Okay. Me too.
那我也這樣選
Judge.
開始判定
We must both be civilians.
我們肯定都是市民
So no one shoots, and we draw.
所以誰都不開槍，這一局打成平局
I'm in the lead by $5,000.
我現在以5000美元領先
If we keep drawing like this, I'll win.
如果這一局打成平局，那我就贏了
What's she gonna do?
她會怎麼做呢？
You're a robber?
強盜？
How?
怎麼會這樣？
Since neither of you fired,
由於兩人均未開槍
Yuki, the robber, wins $5,000.
因此選擇強盜的悠季小姐 獲得五千美元
The safe is reset.
現在重置保險箱
You fell for it.
你中計了
You used it didn't you? Your devil power.
妳使用了惡魔之力，對吧？
Earlier…
之前…
So, Yukky.
小悠季
Shall we finish this?
在這一局決勝負吧？
I used my devil power on the switch.
我對按鍵使用了惡魔之力
CONTAGION PROGRAM
（感染程式）
Shall we swap our cases?
我們要不要互換箱子？
While you were touching the switch,
當你碰到按鍵時
even though you wanted to press "citizen,"
你想按下“市民”鍵
you unintentionally pressed "robbery."
卻會無意識地按下“強盜”鍵
This is my devil power.
這就是我的惡魔之力
SENYA UNINTENTIONALLY CHOSE YUKI TO BE A ROBBER
（潛夜無意識地幫悠季按下強盜鍵）
Contagion Program.
感染程式
ARENA TWO
（第二會場）
End of the final set.
最後一局結束
FINAL SET
（最後一局）
Here are the results. Akira Mori has $15,000,
比賽結果，毛利明獲得一萬五千美元
but Mitsuru Asai has $5,000.
淺井滿獲得五千美元
And so Akira Mori is the winner of the game.
因此這場比賽的獲勝者是毛利明
Thank you very much,
非常感謝
Asai.
淺井君
Shit!
該死
It's my key!
那是我的鑰匙
How fitting for the final set. A hefty sum.
最後一局出現了高額金錢，太合適了
Will you steal or defend the money?
你們要奪走還是看守金錢？
ARENA ONE
（第一會場）
Since it's a tie…
反正我們現在同分
FINAL SET
（最後一局）
…whether it's $10,000 or $1,000, whoever takes this set will win.
所以不管是一萬還是一千美元 拿下這局就贏了
You're right.
是啊
The winner will be decided.
這一局將決出勝負
Yukky,
小悠季
you used your power just now didn't you?
妳剛才用了惡魔之力吧？
What the hell could it be?
這到底是什麼能力呢？
You can only use a devil power once per game,
惡魔之力在每個遊戲中只能使用一次
but my Contagion Program
但是我的“感染程式”
is effective for as long as the game lasts.
只要遊戲持續就一直有效
So he'll keep unintentionally pressing…
所以他會繼續無意識地…
YUKI'S SWITCH
（悠季的按鍵）
…the "robbery" button on my switch.
…在我的按鍵上按下“強盜”鍵
Hey, Yukky.
小悠季
Hurry up and choose "citizen."
趕快選“市民”吧
First, why don't we dial up the tension?
在按下按鍵之前 要不要讓遊戲更刺激一點？
How about we swap guns too?
我們不僅交換箱子 也交換槍吧，怎麼樣？
The guns?
換槍？
What's he up to?
他想做什麼？
Does he know what my power is?
他發現我的惡魔之力了嗎？
No, there's no way he could.
不，不可能
This is the last turn, so why don't we mix it up?
這是最後一局了，我們交換槍吧
That's what gambling's all about, right?
賭博要的就是這種感覺
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Are you too scared?
現在妳害怕了？
Go on then, let's swap.
好啊，那就交換吧
It's okay right?
可以嗎？
I'll allow it.
可以
Thanks.
謝啦
This must be a trap.
這一定是陷阱
He must be about to use his devil power.
這次他肯定要使用惡魔之力了
I don't know what it is,
我不知道他的能力是什麼
but he can only use it once in the game.
但他在遊戲中只能使用一次
So if I can use my devil power to keep it at a tie,
因此我可以 使用我的惡魔之力打成平局
I can extend the game, and gain the upper hand.
如果進入加時賽，情況會對我很有利
Even though you used your devil power,
雖然妳使用了惡魔之力
I admit you played well.
但我得承認，妳表現得還不錯
And you really did a cool job making OROCHI.
能設計出大蛇確實很厲害
You think you've already won?
你覺得自己贏定了？
I'm happy to take over your life,
妳的命交給我就可以了
but I do hope Terurin can do something to save your family.
希望小照照能挽救妳家人的性命
Of course he will.
他一定可以的
I believe in him.
我相信照朝君
That goes without saying.
這毋庸置疑
But,
但是
I'm still going to do everything I can to win
我也會拚盡全力戰勝你
and protect my family. You'll see.
保護我的家人
Don't hate me when I win.
輸了不要恨我
I was going to say the same to you.
這正是我要說的話
Next you'll press "robbery" on my switch.
接下來你會在我的按鍵上 按下“強盜”鍵
Then I will press "robbery" on your switch too.
然後我也會在你的按鍵上
YUKI CHOOSES SENYA TO BE A ROBBER
（悠季幫潛夜選擇強盜）
Judge.
開始判定
He's not firing.
他不開槍
Because we exchanged guns neither of us should shoot.
我們交換了槍 這種情況下，我們都不會開槍
Then it will be a draw, because we are both robbers.
這樣就打成平局了 因為我們都選了強盜
I can extend the game.
比賽將會延長
Yes, you're a robber.
很好，你的畫板是強盜
I'm a robber too, so it's a tie－
我的畫板也是強盜 這一局將會是平局…
No.
怎麼會？
Citizen?
市民？
Because neither of you took a shot,
由於雙方均未開槍
the robber, Senya, takes $10,000.
因此選擇強盜的潛夜先生 獲得一萬美元
The results: Yuki Manabe has $5,000,
比賽結果，真鍋悠季獲得五千美元
and Senya Uesugi has $15,000.
上杉潛夜獲得一萬五千美元
Senya Uesugi is the winner of the game.
這個比賽的獲勝者是上杉潛夜
Even more fun than expected.
這場比賽比想像中還要有趣
Thanks to you, Yukky.
謝啦，小悠季
How? How can I be a citizen?
為什麼？我怎麼會是市民？
It's not possible.
這不可能
Your power was the ability to command others?
妳的能力是操縱對手的行動吧？
I guess the power was hidden in the switch?
而且這個能力隱藏在按鍵中？
Just like I thought.
我猜對了
How?
你是怎麼做到的？
A pin?
圖釘？
I thought of it.
我已經想到了
I wanted to press "citizen,"
我本來想按“市民”鍵
but I guess your power made me press "robbery" instead.
但妳的惡魔之力 讓我無意識按下了“強盜”鍵
So I put a pin on the "robbery" button,
所以我在“強盜”鍵上放了一根圖釘
and tried to press "citizen."
然後試著按“市民”鍵
And then, just as I thought…
果然不出我所料
Even a devil power beyond human knowledge
惡魔之力雖然超越了人類的認知
can be dealt with once you know the source.
但掌握根源就能有應對的辦法
The point is…
應對的關鍵就是…
I shouldn't try to press "robbery."
只要不按“強盜”鍵就行了
So I didn't touch the switch directly with my hand,
所以我沒有直接用手觸碰按鍵
but I managed to press "citizen."
而是用別的辦法按下“市民”鍵
With this pen. See?
我用的是這支筆
Yuki's power
悠季小姐的惡魔之力
only works if the opponent touches the object directly.
只在對手直接觸碰物體時有效
Because he used a pen, the power did not work.
當他使用筆時，這個能力便無法生效
Senya, you didn't use a devil power?
這麼說，你沒有使用惡魔之力？
If you think using a devil power is always better, you're wrong.
如果妳認為使用惡魔之力就一定有利 那就錯了
Sometimes not using it is a better strategy.
有時候不使用反而更有利
Devil powers are very strong.
惡魔之力確實很強大
There are times when the true power of the trump card is not using it.
但有時候不亮出底牌才是致勝關鍵
I lost.
我輸了
Time to settle the bets.
現在清算賭注
Yuki Manabe, the defeated,
敗者真鍋悠季
will entrust her life to Senya Uesugi, the winner.
要將自己的性命交給勝者上杉潛夜
This brings the game Gold Gun &amp; Silver Gun to an end.
“金槍和銀槍”遊戲到此結束
For a couple of pitifully stupid humans, that was a fun game!
以兩個愚蠢又可悲的人類來說 這場遊戲真有趣
See ya, El-chin.
再見啦，小埃埃
I'll take that.
我拿走了
Mom.
媽媽
Kazuma!
一馬
Yuki.
悠季
Your mom and brother are safe.
妳媽媽和一馬沒事了
Terurin?
小照照
We were pulled into a game at the radio tower by Gungnir.
其實我們在電波塔那裡 也被迫參加了永恆之槍設計的遊戲
"Believe in the path you are on."
“相信你走的道路”
WATCH OUT FOR DRONES
（小心無人機）
We only have 30 seconds!
只剩30秒了
"A new path will appear."
”這樣就能開闢新道路“
We're not gonna make it.
再不走就來不及了
You have to run, Teruasa!
照朝，快走啊
WATCH OUT FOR DRONES
（小心無人機）
BEWARE OF ROCKS
（當心岩石）
CONGRATULATIONS GAME CLEARED
（恭喜，闖關成功）
It stopped.
太好了，停止倒數了
OROCHI, hurry.
大蛇，快
Roger!
收到
Once we cleared the game and stopped the detonation,
我們在成功闖關並阻止爆炸後
OROCHI connected to the Internet,
大蛇連上了網路
and hacked into traffic and car cameras at the time they were abducted.
並駭入了 他們被綁架時的道路和汽車監視器
I contacted Ryukan, and Hyodo was with him.
我聯繫了龍肝先生，那時兵頭也在
The two of them went to help.
他們一起把人救出來了
It's okay.
沒事了
You're Yuki's mother? And her brother, Kazuma?
你們是悠季的媽媽和弟弟一馬嗎？
Yes.
是的
Thank goodness.
太好了
I'm so relieved.
真的太好了
Thank you.
謝謝
Seriously?
不會吧？
I lost a bet against Terurin.
我跟小照照打賭輸了
Senya.
潛夜
If I hadn't made it in time,
如果我趕不及的話
what would you have done?
你會怎麼做？
I always knew you'd make it.
我相信你一定能趕上的
How can you say that?
你還好意思這麼說
Bullshit.
最好是
You were all very impressive.
各位，你們都辛苦了
-Well done on your first win. -Do I get something?
-恭喜你們在第一輪中獲勝 -有獎勵嗎？
You too, Teruasa Oda.
你和織田照朝都有
You played a brilliant game. A feast for the eyes.
你的比賽也很精彩，非常值得一看
They were watching us after all.
他們果然透過攝影機監視我們
I saved the hostages.
我救出了人質
I don't give a damn about the hostages.
我根本不在乎那些人質
She participated in the tournament.
她參加了錦標賽
That was my goal.
我的目的就達成了
What is Gungnir's plan behind all this?
永恆之槍到底有何意圖？
I'm looking forward to the next game.
我非常期待下一輪比賽
Wait!
等等
I'll leave the rest to you.
後面的就交給你了
The creation of a new world map.
他們打算創造新的世界地圖
Gungnir is using the devil's keys
永恆之槍要使用惡魔鑰匙
to reclaim this filthy world,
重塑這個骯髒的世界
and create a new one
從而打造一個新世界
under the leadership of Our Great Guide.
一切都由偉大的引領者領導
Guide?
引領者？
Gungnir has 50 devil's keys.
永恆之槍已經擁有50把惡魔鑰匙了
Then what is the aim of the tournament?
那這個錦標賽的目的是什麼？
If you want to know that, you'll have to beat me.
你想知道的話，得先戰勝我
-Ui－ -However,
-初… -不過
the next round is a team game.
下一輪是團體賽
Team?
團體賽？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
-What has Gungnir done to you? -I will beat you.
-永恆之槍對你做了什麼？ -我會擊敗你的
"Basket Fruits."
“水果籃”
You must guess what kind of fruit, and how many are in the basket.
你們要猜出籃子中有什麼水果 還有數量是多少
Human betrayal is a sweet thing.
人類的背叛真有看頭
There was some kind of underground facility?
這裡有某種地下設施？
-Come on. -I will beat you no matter what.
-來吧 -我一定會打敗你的